(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
Oh!
Yeah, let's go!
Huh?
What the flip?!
Dang it... oh...
Oh man... what's going on?
Where... where am I?
Huh?
No way! Did I get sucked into the game world?
Whoa... what do I do?
Hello? Hello?
Oh, why are there so many eyes on me?
They're not saying anything.
Oh, I have to get back!
Today is such an important day,
I can't get stuck in here!
What should I do?
I guess I have to figure this out on my own.
Um... There's so many people looking at me...
Are those Pebbles? Hello!
Are you expecting me to do something?
Maybe I should sing and dance,
'cause this looks like a stage.
Maybe...
Wait, is that how I get out?
Okay... Okay, I got it then!
I'm gonna sing and dance a song right now!
Here we go!
This game!
まわり続ける 歯車にはなり下がらない
I won't settle for being a gear that just keeps spinning
平均演じる 誕生から始まった地獄
Playing it safe, a hell that started from birth
遊び半分で 神が導いた 盤上の世界
A game for fun, a board-game world guided by gods
No no no game no life
ぬるい平穏を ばっさり切り捨てて
Cutting away this lukewarm peace
栄光の階段に 存在刻むんだ
Carving my existence into the stairs of glory
目に映るのは 完全勝利の運命
What I see is the fate of complete victory
何もかも 計算通り 変えてやる
I'll change everything exactly as planned
止まらない空白で
With an unstoppable blank space
We are Maverick
救済なんていらない
I don't need any salvation
どんな理不尽も 覆せばいいだけ
I just have to overturn any absurdity
の話
That's all there is to it
才能の駆け引きと
A strategic battle of wits
才能が 無敗誘う
And talent invites invincibility
生まれ落ちた日の手で 楽しむんだ
I'll enjoy it with the hands I was born with
自分だけを 自分 信じてる
I believe in myself, only myself
底に潜む 闇より強い相手はいない
There's no opponent stronger than the darkness lurking at the bottom
挫けぬ限り そこに敗北はあり得ない
As long as I don't falter, defeat is impossible
表向きの個性に 安住と引き換えに
In exchange for settling for a superficial identity
プライド殺すな
Don't kill your pride
No no no sense of life
野蛮な雑音を きっぱり蹴飛ばして
Kicking away the savage noise
誰より純粋な 声上げるんだ
I'll raise a voice purer than anyone's
戦うことは きっと間違いじゃない
Fighting is surely not a mistake
手応えが 教えてくれた
The feeling of it told me so
全て失っても 勝ち残れ
Even if I lose everything, I will survive
We are Maverick
常識なんていらない
I don't need any common sense
前ならえ向かう 先に待ってるのは
What's waiting ahead of following the lead
退屈な王座に
On a boring throne...
いなけりゃつまらない
It's boring if I'm not there
挑んでやる
I'll take the challenge
生まれ落ちた命も 駒にして
Making even the life I was born with into a piece
自分だけの道を 最後まで
Running my own path until the very end
迷わない 選ばれし者の 真っ赤な自惚れでも
I won't hesitate, even if it's the sheer conceit of the chosen
誇らしく 生き抜くための 方法を一つしか知らないから
Because I only know one way to live proudly
We are Maverick
救済なんていらない
I don't need any salvation
どんな理不尽も 覆せばいいだけ
I just have to overturn any absurdity
の話
That's all there is to it
才能の駆け引きと
A strategic battle of wits
才能が 無敗誘う
And talent invites invincibility
生まれ落ちた日の手で 楽しむんだ
I'll enjoy it with the hands I was born with
この世界手にして 笑うんだ
I'll take this world in my hands and laugh
We are Maverick
最強の空白
The strongest blank
空白ならば 何物にも 何物にもなれる
If we're blank, we can become anything, anything
自分だけを 自分 信じてる
I believe in myself, only myself
Yeah! How was that? That was the best performance ever, right?
Hey! Over there! You liked it, right? Hey!
With this, I should be able to get back to my own world.
All right! Ready? Beam me up, Pebbles!
No!
Pebbles! Where are you going?
Dang it.
Well, according to video game logic, this must mean I must now go on an epic quest to find the coins or something.
But I don't have time for that!
I need the coins back to get home! No!
Huh?
Oh, what's this?
I mean, I came out through there,
so maybe this will take me, you know, on my next step of my quest?
Well, better than being stuck here.
So...
Let's go!
Ah!
I'm not back in my world?
え？ ここどこ？
Eh? Where is this?
待ってたよ、ビブー
I've been waiting for you, Biboo.
Robocosan Joins the Battle! Fighting Game Battle
Eh? Eh?
Roboco-senpai?
探しているのは… これ？
Is this... what you're looking for?
Ah! Coin! The coin!
MISSION: Reclaim the scattered coins from each stage's Game Master!
これがないと元の世界に戻れないんでしょう。
Without this, you won't be able to return to your world, right?
でも、そうはさせない。
But I won't let that happen.
ゲームマスターである僕たちから 全て取り戻せるかな？
Can you take everything back from us, the Game Masters?
え？ 本当？
Eh? Really?
まあ、とにかくこのコインが欲しければ、
Well, anyway, if you want this coin,
僕と勝負だ！
you'll have to challenge me!
Match?
そう、イエス！
So, yes!
格闘ゲームで勝負だ！
Challenge me in a fighting game!
All right, I won't lose!
リモコン
Remote Controller
これが私をリモコン操作（かんたん）コントロールする機械です
This is the machine that remote-controls me with ease.
少しイビツな形をしておりますが使えますか？
It's a bit of an odd shape, but can you use it?
もうちょっとで外に出られるのにな
I was so close to getting outside.
どうやってもうまく行かね
No matter what I do, it doesn't go well.
まだまだ、まだまだ足りない
It's not enough, not enough yet.
Sit down, please!
回転（まわ）して、回転（まわ）して
Turn it around, turn it around.
Turn around!
どうやって踊りましょうか？
How shall we dance?
まだまだ、まだまだ踊り足りない
Still, still not enough dancing.
Dancing night!
踊って、踊って
Dance, dance.
Singing now!
あのコよりも上手く歌いたい
I want to sing better than that girl.
これが僕をリモコンで操縦できる機械です
This is the machine that allows me to be controlled by remote.
説明書は紛失しておりますが使えますか？
The instruction manual is missing, but can you use it?
カラフルなベルみたいな いつもの顔
Your usual face, like a colorful bell
余裕でしょ
Easy, right?
今日はかなり 本気だぜ
Today I'm quite serious
ほら すぐ決めて
Look, decide now
座る 座る Sit down please
Sit down, sit down, please
特等席を頭に刺して
Stick the best seat in your head
回る 回る Turn around
Turn around, turn around
ちょっと待って スタンバイ状態
Wait a second, standby mode
踊る 踊る Dancing night
Dance, dance, dancing night
ジャストフィットなリズムを出して
Give me a just-fit rhythm
唸り上げる Singing now
Roaring out, singing now
あいつよりも高く歌いたい
I want to sing higher than them
惚れた腫れたの七色ザムライ
Fallen in love, seven-colored samurai
洗いざらい主張する存在
An existence that claims everything
思い違いが透けてるアンバイ
A state where misunderstandings are transparent
怖いぐらいの枠外状態
An out-of-the-box state that's almost scary
気にしないのがあなたのポリシー
Not caring is your policy
悩んでいてもお腹は減るし
Even if you're worried, you get hungry
なんだかんだで世間はヘルシー
Somehow the world stays healthy
おきをたしかに ぬるま湯ダンシン
Get a grip, lukewarm water dancing
もうちょっとでスキマ埋まるのに
Just a little more and the gap will be filled
どうやってもうまくいかねえ
No matter what, it doesn't go well
ああもう時間が足りない
Ah, there's just not enough time
座る 座る Sit down please
Sit down, sit down, please
ひっくり返り体が溶けて
Flipped over, my body's melting
巡る 巡る Turn around
Turn around, turn around
唸り上げて スタンバイ状態
Roaring out, standby mode
踊る 踊る Dancing night
Dance, dance, dancing night
マッシュアップで漏れなく上がる
Raising the roof in this mashup
声をあげて Singing now
Raise your voice, singing now
あの子みたいな瞳になりたい
I want to have eyes like that girl
座る 座る Sit down please
Sit down, sit down, please
巡る 巡る Turn around
Turn around, turn around
踊る 踊る Dancing night
Dance, dance, dancing night
声をあげて Singing now
Raise your voice, singing now
あの子みたいな瞳になりたい
I want to have eyes like that girl
Wahoo!
I win!
Nooo!
大丈夫?
Are you okay?
あ! コイン! ヤッター!
Ah! A coin! Yay!
コインゲット!
I got a coin!
Go to the next stage...
But be careful.
次のゲームマスターは僕のようにはいかないぞ
The next game master won't be as easy as me.
No easy?
Not easy?
大丈夫だよ! ビブーだから!
It's okay! Because I'm Biboo!
Oh, okay.
うん! ありがとう先輩!
Yup! Thank you, Senpai!
じゃあ、バイバイ!
Well then, bye-bye!
Bye bye!
Bye-bye!
Wah! There! Whoo!
Now then, where to next, I wonder?
We've been waiting for you, Biboo!
Wow!
IRyS Ninomae Ina'nis Joins the Battle! Driving Battle
えっ? アイリス! イナ!
Huh? IRyS! Ina!
I'm assuming this is what you're looking for, right?
Why are you guys so cool?
Yes, yes! I need that! I need that! Yes! Give it, give it!
We won't just hand it over.
You'll have to race us for it.
Yes.
No way! Give it! Where are you putting that?
I'm putting that back in my pocket.
Where is it going?
No, if you want it, you have to beat us.
Are you ready to battle?
Fine! I'll be cool too, watch this!
Oh hey! I wumbo, you wumbo!
One, two, three, go! No one can stop us tonight!
No one can stop us shine!
No one can stop us tonight!
Save me, I think I'm freezing up
So cold inside
Save me, I need a guiding touch
In these dark times
Inside the maze of your heart
I'm the soul that strays
But baby look at me, you're not blind
Oh, can't you see that I can be refined
Your heart is super hot right now, it's time
To be your diamond girlfriend
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, untouchable
Silver flames consuming me
Let them light the way
Diamond girlfriend, go, go, go, go
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakening
So break it all, break it all, break it all
The diamond girlfriend
Get up, get up, your hit
Be on my side
巻き散らすノア Bling bling no sparkle
Scattering Noah, bling bling no sparkle
Just hit it and wheel it
Make us all party
眩しいスターズ Make a grand jam
Dazzling stars, make a grand jam
Trust me, your weary eyes betray
what you've tried to hide 僕らの明日へと舞い降り
what you've tried to hide, swooping into our tomorrow
Trust me, I'll never shy away from your dark side
響き渡る声
A voice that echoes through
Under the pressure and fires
These ashes reborn, your birth
Let me show you who I really am
In the name of love I'll be a...
Your heart is super hot right now, it's time
To be your diamond girlfriend
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, untouchable
Silver flames consuming me
Let them light the way
Diamond girlfriend, go, go, go, go
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakening
So break it all, break it all, break it all
No one can dull my shine tonight
Now C's your atomic symbol
ぐるぐる回る真っ赤になるまで Wimbo
Spinning around until it turns red, wimbo
愛が足りないとか闇が深いほど
When love isn't enough or the darkness is deep
Catch up, gem, I'll go I'm a jeweler so
踊りなさい！
Dance!
Shine on, shine bright
Like my flame
Until it all melts away
Are you ready?!
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, untouchable
Silver flames consuming me
Let them light the way
Diamond girlfriend, go, go, go, go
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakening
So break it all, break it all, break it all
No one can dull my shine tonight
やったー！
I did it!
うおー！
Whoo!
Are you guys okay?
Yeah...
That hit you hard?
God damn it! I did it!
I got the coin! I'm the winner!
I win!
あ、何これ？ポータル？
Oh, what's this? A portal?
ポータルだ
It's a portal.
By the way, where did the coin come from, IRyS?
えっ、それは...
Uh, it...
It came from my Nephilim pocket!
行くよー！バイバイ！
I'm going! Bye bye!
うわああ、目が回る！うおお！
Ahhh, the world is spinning! Whoa!
お、目が回る...
Oof... dizzy...
ん？ここがパズルステージ？
Huh? Is this the puzzle stage?
よし！次の挑戦の準備はできてるよ！出ておいで！おい！
Hey! I'm ready for my next challenge now! Hey, come out! Hey!
Huh?
There's no Game Master this time?
Eh... Well, I guess I could use a break or something then.
Hmm... maybe I'll dance and sing by myself,
you know, as a refresher!
Yeah, so I'll be ready for the next challenge!
This is a puzzle stage, so it does remind me of a certain song...
Hey! Everyone over there! You want to hear it too, right?
Yeah?
Okay, they didn't say anything, I'm just talking to myself.
Well, alright then! Let's dance,
Tetris!
テトリス (Tetris)
Tetris
どして どして どしてしまんの
Why, why, why does it happen?
どしん どして どしんしてまの
Thud, why, thudding away?
どしん どして いんつきましょうか
Thud, why, shall we breathe in?
悪くない
Not bad
興味ね 即位 派手感動
No interest, enthronement, flashy excitement
除備ね 薬 食べば ど
Preparation, if you eat the medicine...
貯備して 振る 見てめ 暗号化
Storing, shaking, look, it's encrypted
金による
Depends on money
常識で 狂い プロラント
Going crazy with common sense, pro-lant
ポチゲーで インケル バンド
Inkel band with a clicker game
疎信で 苦し どめ 貫通は
Suffering with sparse messages, the penetration is...
草生える
LOL
どして どすぐ 見てしまんの
Why, why did I look so quickly?
どして どすぐ いてしまんの
Why, why did I go so quickly?
どして どすぐ 壊れちゃかな
Why, why did it break so quickly?
近未来式 買っかったん
I bought a near-future style one
ショッピングモール 現代 コンフィ
Shopping mall, modern comfy
正味どして 買っかったん
Honestly, why did I buy it?
文字放る 経理 ピンボール
Throwing letters, accounting pinball
ワールドサイズ 百個ずつ足してゆき
World size, adding a hundred at a time
ゆず色添え テテテテテテテテ
With a hint of citron, te-te-te-te...
テトリス どうしてこんな目に
Tetris, why am I in this situation?
興味がないことほど 本気じゃないもの全部
The things I'm not interested in, the things I'm not serious about,
後回しにして 知ってることは知らんぷり
I put them all off, and pretend not to know what I know.
私は終わっている 恥ずかしい過去を知ってる奴らの
I'm finished. For those who know my embarrassing past,
記憶消させて 迷惑かけて ごめんてばね
Let me erase their memories. I'm sorry for being a bother.
誰か助けて
Somebody help me!
どして どすぐ 光っちゃうの
Why, why does it shine so quickly?
知りたくない 知りたくない 知りたくない
I don't want to know, don't want to know, don't want to know!
もみね どすぐ 光っちゃぞ
Already, it's gonna shine soon!
貯金で 買いた 窓
The window I bought with my savings...
行きたくない 行きたくない 行きたくない
I don't want to go, don't want to go, don't want to go! Bye bye!
銀時期優先 ポール
Silver period priority pole
ナイチンゲールな配信ゲーム
A Nightingale-like streaming game
飯ほか 飲みマシン
Meal and drink machine
借金 ボールで ちりちり ハイボール
Sizzling highball with a debt ball
御殿旅行 そよ風 食事つき
A trip to a palace, with a breeze and meals included
早く生きて テテテテテテテテ
Live quickly, te-te-te-te...
テトリス 強化 練習中
Tetris, currently in intensive training!
嘘とか 外界 忙しくて
Lies and the outside world, so busy that...
眠れないわけ 今日も
I can't sleep today either.
誰か早く 殴って 気絶させてくれよ
Somebody, quickly, punch me and knock me out!
人生にキャンセル キャンセル界隈
Cancelling life, the cancellation neighborhood...
ぼんやりとした不安 私のせい 私が悪いよ
A vague anxiety. It's my fault, I'm the one who's bad.
そうだよ
That's right.
興味が出ても 本気でやっても
Even if I get interested, even if I do it for real,
全部空回りで
It's all just spinning my wheels.
知らないくせに 嘘つき私は終わっている
Even though I don't know, a liar like me is finished.
恥ずかしい過去を知ってる奴らの 記憶消させて
Let me erase the memories of those who know my embarrassing past.
迷惑かけて ごめんてばね
I'm sorry for being a bother.
誰か助けて
Somebody help me!
迷惑かけて ごめんてばね
I'm sorry for being a bother.
誰か許して！
Somebody forgive me!
Whoa! Ah!
Wait, dizzy... dizzy...
What scared me?
I didn't know this game's bugged, man!
Hey, someone report these bugs, dang it!
Cubes start popping out and everything!
Who designed this? I need to meet the devs!
Hey devs! This game is malfunctioned...
But I don't have time for that, I gotta find the coins!
Eh? Oh!
I guess that's my cue to leave!
Okay, next stage! Let's charge up!
Helicopter! Helicopter!
Oh!
どうもどうも、待ってましたよ、びーぶー！
Hello, hello! I've been waiting for you, Biboo!
Shirakami Fubuki Joins the Battle! Crane Game Battle
Fubuki-senpai!
びーぶーは、これが欲しいんだよね？
Biboo, you want this, right?
Kawaii! Hoshii, hoshii!
Cute! I want it, I want it!
ならば白上と勝負だ！
Then, it's a match with Shirakami!
白上のクレーンゲームから果たして逃げられるかな？
I wonder if you can escape from Shirakami's crane game?
Okay then... 負けないよ！
Okay then... I won't lose!
LONELY ROLLING STAR
陽だまり
Laying in the sun
サンサン
Brilliant sun
ココロは
The heart is
ハレ模様
Clear weather
二つの
Two
瞳は
Eyes
ヒマワリ
Sunflower
の種のよう
Just like seeds
語らい
Lovers' chats
重なり
Pile up, overlapping
カタマリ
A katamari
カラマリ
An entanglement
一緒に
Being
いること
Together
絶対
Absolute
必然
Necessity
でも あなた 大事な夢を描く
Except you are drawing out your important dream
終わるまでは ずっと
Until you're finished,
そう ここで待っている
I'll be right here waiting for you
You're lonely rolling star
立ち止まらないで ねえ
Don't you ever stop!
You're lonely rolling star
さあ 前を向いて行こう
So, face forward and keep going!
星空
A sky of stars
キラキラ
Sparkling and glittering
コンペイトウ のよう
Like dots of sugar candy...
甘くて
Sweet
切ない
Painful
想いが
My feelings
募るの
Are growing
抱きしめた 想いは
The feelings I held in my heart
夜空を舞い
Fly through the night sky
急降下して
And dive down
あなたの元へ
To reach you
届くかな
I wonder if they will reach?
YOU ARE LONELY ROLLING STAR
あきらめないで よね
Don't give up
YOU ARE LONELY ROLLING STAR
大好き 待ってあの場所で
I love you, wait for me at that place
待ち合わせよう 丘で
Let's meet up on the hill
立ち止まらないで ねえ
Don't you ever stop!
思い出してよね
Please remember me
待っててね
Wait for me, okay?
Ah, there! I think we're doing great now, aren't we?
Who's next, huh? I'm ready for my next challenge!
待っていたぞ、ビブー
I've been waiting for you, Biboo.
Todoroki Hajime Joins the Battle! Rhythm Dance Battle
Hajime? What?!
これが欲しければ私と勝負だ
If you want this, you'll have to face me!
My coin!
はじめのダンスについて来られるかな？
Can you keep up with Hajime's dancing?
Eh? Dance? Hm...
Okay! Let's dance together! Ya! Ya!
みんなー！ チルノのさんすう教室はじまるよー！
Everyone! Cirno's Math Class is starting!
あたいみたいな天才目指して、がんばっていってね！
Aim to be a genius like me and do your best!
キラキラ ダイアモンド
A sparkling diamond,
輝く星のように
just like a shining star.
栄光 志望校 なんとかして入ろう
Glory, the school of my dreams, I'll get in somehow.
天才 秀才 トップ目指して GO GO！！
Genius, prodigy, aim for the top, GO GO!!
バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot!
「あたい、バカじゃないもん！」
"I'm not an idiot!"
バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot!
「バカって言うほうがバカなのよ！」
"The one calling me an idiot is the idiot!"
バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot!
「何よ、うるさいわねこのバカ！」
"What, you're so noisy, you idiot!"
バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot!
紅魔館から バスが出て
A bus left from the Scarlet Devil Mansion...
はじめに三人 乗りました
...with three people initially on board.
白玉楼で 一人降りて
One person got off at Hakugyokurou...
半人だけ 乗りました
...and only a half-phantom boarded.
八雲さんちで 一人降りて
One person got off at the Yakumo residence...
結局乗客 合計何人だ？
...in the end, what's the total number of passengers?
答えは答えは 0人0人
The answer is, the answer is 0, 0!
なぜならなぜなら それは 幻想郷にバス無い
Because, because, there are no buses in Gensokyo!
山落ち 意味など無いわ キャラクター立てばいいのよ
Meaningless wordplay; it's fine as long as the characters stand out!
元気があれば何でも 1 2 9!
If you have energy, anything is possible! 1, 2, 9!
くるくる 時計の針
Round and round go the clock hands,
ぐるぐる 頭まわる
round and round my head spins.
だって つぶら目玉 二つしかないのに
Since I only have two round eyes,
三本の針なんて ちんぷんかん
three clock hands are just gibberish!
つぎつぎ 問題出る
Problems come one after another,
まだまだ 授業続く
the class still continues on.
凍る部屋の中 ひんやりした温度も
In the frozen room, don't mind the chilly temperature,
時間も気にせず ゆっくりしていってね
or the time, and take your time!
バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot!
「だからバカじゃないって言ってるでしょ！」
"I told you I'm not an idiot!"
バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot!
「いい加減にしないと冷凍するわよ！」
"If you don't stop, I'll freeze you!"
「そして粉々になって死ねばいいのよ！」
"And then you can just crumble and die!"
バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot!
霊夢んとこの 百万円の
Someone broke the million-yen vase...
壺を誰かが 割っちゃった
...at Reimu's place.
永遠亭の えーりんが
Eirin from Eientei...
弁償に来ましたよ
...came to pay for it.
知らんぷりの イタズラで
Due to some play-innocent prank...
結局賠償金額 いくら？
...what was the final compensation amount?
答えは答えは 0人0人
The answer is, the answer is 0, 0!
なぜならなぜなら それは そんな壺あるわけない
Because, because, there's no way such a vase exists!
常識超えたところに 世界の真理がある
Beyond common sense lies the truth of the world,
秘密の数字目指して 1 2 9!
aiming for the secret number! 1, 2, 9!
ヘラヘラ ニヤけながら
Grinning foolishly,
ゲラゲラ 笑いながら
laughing loudly!
Uwah!
Phew...
Oh! Oh, we're already... okay.
Ah, I see.
Wow! What's next then?
The rest is... let me count...
One... two...
Tonight, tonight, tonight
I'm screaming on the inside
Sign of heart, sign of heart, sign of heart
Already for this art
Gotta faith, gotta faith beyond the unknown
It's the only way to live
Ready to go, ready to go, ready to go
Somewhere I've never been
What's up?
What's down?
Make it out alive
Set this world on fire now
Whoa, whoa
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you burn out
Whoa, whoa
We're gonna make it out alive
Make it out alive
Set this world on fire now
Whoa, whoa
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you burn out
Whoa, whoa
We're gonna make it out alive
Yeah, make it out, make it out, we're gonna make it out alive
全部倒すなんてすげーじゃん
That was amazing, taking them all down!
あ、終わった？
Oh, is it over?
しゃーねー、よし、コインをやろう！
Alright, well, let's give you a coin!
おー！コイン、やったー！
Oh! A coin, yay!
じゃ、みんな、ありがとうね！
Well, thank you everyone!
あい、ハッピー、ハッピーバースデー！
Happy, happy birthday!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Oh, thank you so much!
オッケー！
Okay!
じゃあ！
Then!
さよならー！
Goodbye!
くそ！ なぜ出られない？
Damn! Why can't we get out?
Nice landing, yeah.
Huh?
Oh, it's the first stage.
Maybe this is like a progress check sort of thing.
Let's see, let's see where I'm at. Huh?
Oh, I'm missing one more coin, but...
where could it be?
Is anyone here to give me another game or something?
Hello?
Maybe this is like the safe zone where I can take a break and recover.
That's a good idea.
You know, I'm feeling kind of tired...
and all these songs have been so beepy intense.
Let's take a break.
I'll just... a nap. I'll be... I'll wake up...
Bye, everyone.
Just give me like five minutes, okay? Just five minutes.
おやすみよ
Goodnight.
You know, おやすみ, おやすみ。
You know, goodnight, goodnight.
Flow
Lyrics: Kathryn Cwynar, Natsuko Ishikawa
Music: Masayoshi Soken
Well come and well met, my brave little spark
How long you've wandered, burned bright as a star
Oh, I have awaited you patiently all this time
patiently all this time
Past every fate
Now sing with me once more
share of your life
Far greater than memory, its loss and love
words cannot hold
Boundless the tale overflows
And carries your light out to sea
Remember the rain, near and far beloved
Each drop a blessing from heavens above
And how as time flowed on those waters became one
Streams, rivers and lakes
Reaching for the horizon and far beyond
They carry onward however changed
with each brief reflection, by setting sun
By storms' wake
Til welcomed home to gentle sea
Sinking deeper and deeper in calm embrace
Leaving tides sweep in and bear you down
Should you meet a soul rising surface-ways
With your unbeating heart wish them well
Deep, dark, far away
I have heard your voice
weighed your every choice
Now our hands join round
the meaning you sought
I'll catch your tears
quench your fears
with joy til you near the shore
Where in time, all shall as hope be reborn
and...
Hush, love, close your eyes
and in sleep abide
As sun's distant light
echoes down to dreams below
Know you will wake
on winds rise again
For this journey's end is but one step
forward to tomorrow
Whoa!
What a good dream!
All right, let's check our progress then.
Hmm, we're still missing one coin.
Where could it be?
I've been waiting for you, Bijou.
Fake Biboo Joins the Battle!
You... you're...
I'm you.
Me?
You mean... my last opponent is me?
Exactly.
Me, you.
Your biggest enemy,
your biggest obstacle...
...yourself.
No!
You've done well at making it this far, Bijou.
But I don't intend to hold back.
Then I won't either!
This stage is too important for me to give up now!
I feel like I'm losing hope
In my body and my soul
And the sky,
it looks so ominous
And as time comes to a halt
Silence starts to overflow
My cries
are inconspicuous
Tell me God, are
you punishing me?
Is this the price I'm paying
for my past mistakes?
This
is my redemption song
I need you more than ever right now
Can you hear me now?
'Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
I wish that someway, somehow
That I could save every one of us
But the truth is that I'm only one girl
Maybe if I keep believing
My dreams will come to life
Come to life
溢れる涙
Overflowing tears
こぼれる命
Spilling life
風は
The wind...
今も遠く
...is still far away
剥がれる錆びと
Peeling rust and
渦巻く刃
swirling blades
誓う
I swear
いつも森に
always to the forest
これが僕の
This is my
呪い
curse
約束
A promise
殺す痛みか
the pain of killing
キミの
Your...
願い
...wish
最後の夢を捨てた
I discarded my last dream
償いたいだけと
Just wanting to atone
そう僕らは今
Yes, we are now
ああ
Ah...
無意味でも叫ぶ
...shouting even if it's meaningless
この汚れた世界 愛
loving this dirty world
そう僕らは今
Yes, we are now
ああ
Ah...
無意味でも願う
...praying even if it's meaningless
ただキミとの時間を
just for time with you
溺れた意識は
The drowned consciousness is
優しいまま
still gentle
消えて
disappearing
Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう僕らは今
Cause we're gonna shout it loud
ああ 無意味でも願う
Even if our words seem meaningless
ただ君との未来を
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
Still, we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう僕らは今
Still, we're gonna shout it loud
ああ 無意味でも願う
Even if our words seem meaningless
ただ君との時間を
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
祈りよ
I hope that somehow
歌しを
That I could save every one of us
得られずとも
Maybe if I keep believing
My dreams will come to life
僕は
I...
Impressive.
Yes! The coin!
Oh, you're still alive. Oh.
You who have defeated all the game masters shall be rewarded.
Huh? What is this?
Now, show this to everyone.
Yeah! Hey, thanks! But, um...
There can only be one!
Hah!
Oh, oh, I'm here. Oh, oh, hah-hah-hah!
Hello everyone! We have made it to the final stage!
You didn't think I collected all those coins and played all those games for nothing, did you?
No, because I'm cashing it in! With all of these coins we have unlocked...
My new original song! Woohoo!
And guess what? The video's gonna come out right after this!
Good job everyone! And I'm gonna perform it to you right now!
Are you ready? Let's go out with a bang! ROCK IN!
Biboo's here to play
Yeah, uh-huh
Ah, ah
Woke up in the morning
I had a funny dream
I was a stone that had been thrown
No way back, I was all in
What if that was me soaring straight to the top?
Let's take a chance, game on, and shoot my shot
Log in, get good, you mad? Let's look,
talk beep, get hit, clean sweep
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo, Biboo
Come and test your luck
Yeah, we're comin' in clutch, Biboo, Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out, one-shot, Biboo, Biboo
Come and help me fight
Get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
Rock in!
BUBUBA BUBUBUBA
YEAH
BUBUBA BAM BAM BA
BUBUBA BUBU
Level up, we go onwards
Aiming for another win
A diamond in the rough, it's kinda tough
You gotta keep on rollin'
The grind goes on and on, no breaks
Seal the cracks with a few band-aids
I'll try over and over and over again
Just one more round, please?
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo-Biboo
Come and test your luck
Yeah we're comin' in clutch, Biboo-Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one-shot, Biboo-Biboo
Come and help me fight
Yeah enough of the jokes just behind you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
Rock in!
Lost in this game, I feel the strain
But I'm pulled back up by your gravity
Your gravity
I see the shape, I feel the space
It's set in stone, carve it into me
I just wanna be
Biboo
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo-Biboo
Come and test your luck
Yeah we're comin' in clutch, Biboo-Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one-shot, Biboo-Biboo
Better hit quicksave 'cause
Biboo's here to play
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo-Biboo
Come and test your luck
Yeah we're comin' in clutch, Biboo-Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one-shot, Biboo-Biboo
Come and help me fight
Yeah enough of the jokes just behind you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
Rock in!
Biboo-Biboo
Ah...
Hello?
Um, I'm still here.
Ready to get teleported back to my world...
any... anytime now?
Mom?
Pick me up! I'm scared.
Hey!
This wasn't part of the deal!
No, wait, what are you doing?
No! No! No! No!
Hey! Listen to my song at least!
Okay, my song's coming out, listen to it!
ROCK IN!
Go! Go!
Ah!